all right it's cohort 4 October 31st 23
and we're in our first discussion of
chapter
nine so today we can totally look at
questions you can look over the chapter
but is there anything that anybody wants
to bring up about chapter
nine
welcome Andrew any general thoughts on
nine modelbased data analysis before we
kind of look through some look over the
structure of the chapter and look over
the
questions okay I have to just hop in to
the uh the structure a good overview
seems nice on this one cool yeah nil had
mentioned epistemology so talk about
leading with a epistemological assertion
the models described in this book are
only useful if they can answer
scientific
questions is that the only way a model
can be useful or is this such a
broad sentiment that everything can be
cast as a scientific question so even
something of purely
epistemological or epistemic
status could could
be under the the scope anyways though in
this chapter we focus on the ways in
which active inference can be applied
understanding empirical data so that's
kind of the big plot twist in chapter
nine is that up
till
here everything has been very much like
proposed as sort of
intrinsically coherent like the rat and
the
te-as or other
um calculations they're all kind of
proposed as um just thought experiments
more than anything else although there's
a lot of citations to the empirical work
like in chapter 5 here though they're
going to go into detail about how you
interface the generative model with
empirical data and so in that way it
kind of complements chapter
six because here we're actually GNA take
that generative model and connect it
with data our general goal is to recover
the parameters of the generative model
that a subject's brain uses to produce
Behavior the subjective model so we'll
see this graphically soon but just to be
clear to recover the
parameters a synonym there would be like
to identify plausible
parameters so if we knew that the height
of children in the classroom was
distributed according to a normal
distribution then we have the data which
is kind of distribution free it's just a
list of numbers and then the task of
chapter nine is basically juxtapose the
structure of that model with the data
and recover the
parameters okay section 9.2 goes into
this metab basian perspective or metab
basian uh
methodology
they bring up two related reasons for
fitting a computational model to observe
Behavior the first is to recover
parameters to give an account of a
single individual from a broader
population or comparing two groups or
two populations or more against each
other so that is taking a fixed model
structure and then multip full samples
of data could be one person on multiple
days or multiple people on multiple days
or whatever the design of the experiment
is and then for a fixed model structure
identify something useful about that
data
like about one group versus another the
second reason is to compare alternative
hypotheses expressed as models that
represent different explanations for
Behavioral phenomena so here instead of
preconditioning on one model we're
actually going to use the data to
interrogate a portfolio of models so we
have performance of multiple individuals
on multiple days so then we might say
okay well the simplest model is all
individuals are the same drawing from
the same distribution all days draw from
the same distribution then we have a
model where individuals don't differ but
days differ then we have individuals
differing but not days and then we have
there's an individual byday interaction
so this is familiar to anyone who's
basically done any kind of statistical
modeling which is that adding more
parameters to a model essentially or
almost by definition always increases
the accuracy of the model on the
training data that doesn't mean it
increases the accuracy in an out of
sample so that's like the training and
test um relationship of overfitting um
but adding parameters basically all
always gets you to fit more
data um or fit the data more closely
however the return on investment per
parameter can
diminish and so that is why in basan
statistics people use methods like the
II information Criterion AIC or the
basian information Criterion
Bic to identify well where are we adding
parameters where's this kind of like
knee or this um special inflection
point where yeah of course we can still
add more parameters and get more fit but
we're like basically at a nice optimal
tradeoff between adding parameters and
fitting the data which is exactly what
variational free energy
is so this is two reasons one is to take
a model identify something interesting
like a pattern in the data the other
which is complimentary is to use data to
identify or differentiate hypothesis in
the world so yeah actually having the
day factor and the individual Factor
those add value but having an individual
bu day we dilute too
much just just like raise your hand if
you have any thoughts if you want to add
anything so this is a pretty standard
statistic
framing here is where we're going to
revisit some of the key Concepts from
earlier in the book like the generative
model of chapter 4 discrete time model
chapter 7 all of this and now we're
going to kind of put it in a laboratory
context so we have the subject of a
behavioral experiment so let's not worry
too much about like objectivity of Truth
and subjectivity of experience but let's
just think about a behavioral study so
the subject of the behavioral study is
the one whom we are developing the
cognitive model
of their cognitive model their
generative model might be about the
laboratory like the
maze however the subject model is what
we've been discussing in basically all
of our kind of agent
Centric cognitive modeling discussions
and then in chapter nine here we're just
going to pop out and add another
dashed ring and a solid box around that
to represent the fact that it's kind of
like now we have the lab and the
subject here's the experimental stimuli
going into the black
box here's the observed Behavior
objectively coming out or could be said
empirically coming
out so this kind of gives a whole
inclosed or closed loop
representation of like the person in the
fmri machine and then here's the
experimental stimuli being provided to
them could be a fixed sequence it could
be drawn from a distribution of stimuli
and then there's the behavioral
outcome
so even the setting of The the
behavioral observational moment the
ethological
setting this is also amenable to basian
statistics so we could talk about
optimal design of experimental
parameters we could talk about
optimal delivery of different
stimuli we could talk about the
information content for different
sequences of
behavior we could do a statistical power
analysis or simulation should we observe
a few individuals for a long time lot of
individuals for a short time these are
like very
empirical laboratory statistical
considerations that will be familiar to
anyone basically doing a behavioral
study or really just any other study
even if it's not like squirrel behavior
but if you have a limited amount of
resources or
time or cameras or whatever it is in the
lab you're going to find yourself
basically in a setting like
this and so that's why this is a really
nice figure and
chapter because it steps outside of just
the kind of abstracted generative model
and now it's like okay now now we're
going to build the setting around
that and so it's kind here's outside the
building
but now it's like the laboratory is like
the marov
blanket around the rat in the
mace which is to say if you control the
laboratory if it's a controlled
experiment then what's happening outside
of the
laboratory shouldn't matter should be
conditionally independent with respect
to the subjective
model so this is kind of compatible with
a lot of
um basian
epistemology in empirical
Sciences okay any thoughts or questions
on that or we'll continue with with n
end of 92 then
it's called metab basian or I don't know
maybe you could say Epi basian or
something double basian because of this
wrapping with a basian statistician
around the basian generative model and
then they even say we're using basian
procedures Twice first to evaluate the
subject's posterior beliefs about
action so posterior means posterior to
the observation so we're going to flash
the red
light then we observe an
action and then we're going to
do parameter recovery about the
subject's posterior beliefs on action
posterior to the observation of the red
light that's the subjective model and
secondly to evaluate our posterior
beliefs about the unknown priors that we
have so it's just a purely basian
approach to studying the total setting
of the behavioral
observation otherwise you'd have this
kind of free floating basian model of
the subject but it would be like a view
from nowhere because you wouldn't have
completed the metab basian
setup okay that's
9.2 9.3 is going to connect us with a
statistical method that's used in a lot
of statistical approximation algorithms
and it's discussed in SPM a lot as well
so variational appuse may be used for
more generic likelihood functions than
incountered earlier which were defined
as gaussian so variational Lao we won't
go through all the details here but um
usually what the llas
approximation is going to do is it's
going to find the single highest point
on the distribution the single maximum
likelihood solution which is why the
um why the likelihood calculation from
earlier matters and then going to fit an
upside down
Parabola so if the distribution has a
central tendency the Vari variational
loss can very well if the distribution
has fat tails or has a multimodal
tendency variational Appo will not do
well if it's gausssum
kind of a technical
subsection but it's possible to
tractably
optimize the variation
Lelo so
it's going to be misleading in some
settings but it's going to be super
useful in some settings but either way
it's very
calculable so it's used for a lot of
statistical
optimizations okay so a
common critique and and valid point that
people often bring up about basy and
statistics is well don't you just get
out what you put it like if your prior
is such and such then don't you just
recover your
prior in the
posterior and there's multiple ways to
address that one of them is if you start
with multiple different priors so from
the same
family parameterized differently or from
different different families and you
recover your prior then you actually can
empirically say that there isn't
information in your data but to the
extent that those diverse priors
Converge on a similar
posterior you can empirically say that
there is signal in the data it's not
binary but those are different heris
that are used so one approach to kind of
get around or to address This reviewer
typee comment that like oh well basian
statistics just returns your
priors is to try different priors and
there's also another approach which is
called parametric empirical base so it's
called empirical because we're taking
empirical data and using that to
initiate the cycle of
optimization so for example if we were
going to be doing a basian model of the
height of the children in the
classroom one approach would be like we
um know that people range from one feet
to 10 feet tall so we're going to do six
feet plus or minus five as a gaan
another approach would be wow we really
don't know it could be between zero and
a th000 feet or something like that like
just try to do this sort of like
purposeful
open-endedness but that might wash out
true signal in the data like even if a
bunch of people were the same exact
height you've only shrunk your
distribution now to between zero and 500
feet
tall so what's the way to get around
that well one is trying multiple prior
sets but another one is to take the
first batch of empirical
data parameterize a gaussian based upon
that and then use that gaussian or an
overd dispersed form of it as your prior
for subsequent analysis
this
discussion on design Matrix so
representing the experimental design as
a
matrix like if we had five people on um
you know multiple different days you
have like data
point1 and then in person a they'll have
a a one and then all zeros for the other
columns
so representing the design Matrix of the
experiment as a matrix and then putting
that within a generalized regression
framework is discussed more in the SPM
textbook than in this
textbook so this is kind of another
technical
subsection talking about how you can use
empirical guidance on initi IAL prior
sets in a generalized linear modeling
setting
with experiments summarized by their
design
Matrix to do a regression on model
coefficients so you can do statistics on
those
coefficients like testing whether the
slope is different than
zero so to go back to the earlier
example where we had like multiple
individuals on multiple
days you could you have the simplest
model no effective individual no
effective day and then you have model
two effective individual model three
effective day model four effect of both
model three effect of both and then you
can
test the relative likelihoods of these
different models and then for whichever
one is the best selected
model then you can say okay the
coefficient was 0.1 plus or minus .5
05 so the slope was two standard
deviations away from
flat so at this Alpha level it was a
statistically significant slope for the
best selected model it's kind of
speeding rapidly through a few different
parts of Statistics but that's basically
what is
happening when you just smash together
the design Matrix and the experimental
Co
efficients you're basically doing a
regression and then you're
calculating essentially A P value based
upon the slope of the regressions
conditioned on the design
Matrix okay so just Al just raise your
hand or unmute if you want to add
anything but just kind of going over
this
chapter
9.5 is a lot like chapter six chapter 6
was the recipe for making a generative
model 9.5 is the instructions for
modelbased analysis so 9.5 is almost
like a Koda to
six so the steps are summarized in
figure
92 first collect data or you might
collect data later and you might do all
these other steps earlier like if you
were going to pre-register the study or
do a simulation or statistical power
calculation so you don't have to collect
the data first again just like chapter
six this is kind of like more like stuff
that has to be done not really a list
that must be done in
order however at the very least you'd
want to know like what sensory input is
available to the subject and what data
you're getting
out sensory data for the subject what
data are coming
out as kind of side note many Studies
have been way layed because there was
sensory data that wasn't intended that
was getting to the subject so I've heard
examples ranging from it was a study of
circadian behavior and there was
Construction in the building so at
certain times a day or during certain
cohorts or replicates there is
sound or just in a Animal Facility
different animal handlers or different
light schedules or different temperature
different air conditioning forest fires
that we had in California like the
sensory inputs available to the subject
doesn't mean just the ones you want and
so that can disrupt a lot of the
statistics but this is basically like
saying what data are are you going to
get from what kind of subject and then
what type of tests are you interested in
doing on that data there's always
exploratory data analysis
Eda um also criticized as being kind of
like a fishing
Expedition so sometimes people go into a
study with really specific hypotheses
other times more
open-ended two formulate a PDP model
if you're using a discrete
time setting which is kind of how how
they're going to do it they're not going
to um template this with A continuous
time model so we get a fully specified
but not solved PDP so structurally
described but not parameterized
PDP specify likelihood
function we could look a little bit more
at SPM mdp
vbx to try to see
exactly
uh what degrees of freedom are
here but I I I my understanding is this
does not this is not something that
needs to be designed on like a per
experiment
level specif prior
beliefs these are the
priors that are being proposed for that
metab
basian setting so if it's kind of a if
it's there's some priors that are
centered on
zero other times you have a prior
distribution over a distribution so it's
like it's bounded by zero and one at
which point you could use uniform or or
some other um proper
distribution solve for posterior
probability standord standard
inference scheme again we could look at
this
routine but this just takes in the above
information and makes a
calculation so the output of steps one
through five is going to be
these estimates of different parameters
of the
model then you can do the group level
analysis
[Music]
um we can look at SPM DCM this is the
dynamic causal
modeling um so that's one approach
that's discussed more in
SPM or you can B basically use any
statistical method canonical variance uh
analysis
CVA similar to The Independent contrasts
I or principal components analysis
PCA or just Anova any number of
statistical
analyses so here's the summary we have
the
data we have the
PDP and the way that it's going to get
calculated all of this gets brought
together so U Tilda Tilda always means
through time and here's U
Tilda the action as selected as observed
Behavior so that's what that's what
we're getting from the data is the
behavior survey data movement data i
gaze
data and then here is going to be a
we're going to get a a likelihood
function for saying what's the
likelihood of given
Behavior conditioned upon the parameters
big
Theta all the
parameters the sequence of observations
received and the generative model
M so that is kind of what the subject is
doing is it's doing this likelihood
calculation what's the likeliest
behavioral sequence given basically all
the parameters accessible to me the
cognitive model as well as the
observations and
then we invert that and that's now
happening on the scientist's
side so we're going to invert so that we
can recover the parameters big
Theta conditioned upon on the model the
observations of the subject and the
action of the
subject that is proportional
to so it it might be off by a
multiplier but it's it's monotonically
proportional
to a
factorized disassembly which is the
parameters given the
model which is something that that
um can be taken off multiplied
by
here exactly what we have
here P of utila conditioned upon Theta
observations in
M
now we can specify our prior beliefs on
this left
side because this is basically our our
beliefs about Theta given the
model and again we would test a range of
these Andor use parametric empirical
base to generate empirically grounded
beliefs but with this inverted model we
can then do statistics on calculation of
theta we have X the design
Matrix beta which is a variable with the
regression coefficients and a noise so
it's kind of like y equal MX plus b plus
noise
term except it's like a mega regression
on a much more sophisticated kind of
data but in the
end here's those five
groups and then here's this one's
parameter range was you know 0 2 plus or
minus one this one was 5 plus or minus
one this was four plus or minus one and
this is like the kind of figure that
you'd get in the paper where there'd be
like a a bar a saying oh these are not
significantly different
Bar B these two are not significantly
different and then an
asterisk saying these two you know
individual one two and three were
significantly different than four and
five at this P
value so chapter six builds us up to
constructing the generative
model if you have empirical data already
at hand or if you intend to collect
empirical data and you already know what
structure it's going to be you kind of
design this complimentary relationship
between the observations that the
generative model is going to get and
then the actions that the generative
model takes which are going to be
observations for the behavioral
scientist and then if the behavioral
scientist can specify this likelihood
model and a prior belief
distribution we can
invert what it is that the subjective
cognitive model is
doing to
recover differences or patterns amongst
parameters for different individuals or
times or
contexts so this takes us from a chapter
six which is just how to build the
generative model and lays out the big
steps for like how we would then get to
the figure for the
paper or to test okay here's five
different doses of a
drug and then on the y- axis is the
attention parameter no variance on this
which is we're going to interpret that
as
attention and here's how it differs
across doses of a
drug so it's a lot of
Statistics here being very very quickly
recited in a
basian cognitive behavioral modeling
setting could you repeat the example
with the drug dosage again yeah so let's
just say we had five different um doses
of drug or control and you know low
medium high and very
high and then um each of those we're
just going to do you know of course you
could have n individuals on N days with
n doses so that' be like a fully
replicated experiment but but you know
you have some some's upset so we five
groups and then we have 30 individuals
per
group um rats so that we don't need to
talk to the IRB or we probably still do
um so then you have the rats do these
different behaviors now if you just
wanted to do statistics on their
behavior you wouldn't even need a
cognitive model so if all you were going
to do was going to do like I'm going to
do the average um percentage of time
moving between the five
groups well then you could just read
that off from the data and just say okay
it was like you know 10% 15% this and
that so you could have a little scatter
plot and then you could say do these
groups statistically different
in the percentage of time moving so that
would just be like literally from the
data to to step
six however you might also have a
cognitive model and so there you would
take that data and then see the actions
of that which the data which are the
actions of the
subject and then utilize this
constructed cognitive
model to do inference on some cognitive
parameter of these five
groups so not simply descriptive
statistics on the action
output and then and then these these
scores are referring to some proposed
cognitive
parameter it's like an example of a
cognitive parameter I'm very interested
in like I like
uh yeah I like that I just want like an
example of
yeah that's a good question
um let's look to some of um the work of
Ryan
Smith okay let's see if this will have a
nice generative
model
some of these
well
perfect so here we see our classic
downstairs
bit figure
4.3 down
downstairs
um the empirical data are going to be
the uh heart
beating
empirically um and then the hidden state
is going to be I believe in this
situation the interception of the
heartbeat and then a which of course
Maps between observations and hidden
States if a were the identity Matrix
this would be a fully observable setting
but of course a isn't exactly the
identity Matrix and in fact they're
interesting in the
Precision so then they can parameterize
this model and you could say um and then
you can um test whether the
Precision the interceptive
awareness differs amongst individuals or
between individuals who have this or
that
diagnosis let's see if there are other
models here's another one this is this
one has to do with um gastrointestinal
perception again we see the
downstairs so then what would be the
next step what would be the way to
integrate action well we know action
intervenes in the B Matrix so now if you
had a descending action
condition and then you could say okay
now do or don't try to pay attention to
your um you know hard you're a
gut and then you could do statistics on
the efficacy of the B
Matrix but now these are making larger
and larger experiments and that's where
you get back to like the resource
limitations and laboratory and stuff
like that but yeah then you could say
well I'm now I'm interested in this
summary statistic
describing the difference between the
average Precision when we do and don't
tell them to do this and there's some
individuals where there's no difference
like telling them to pay attention or
not didn't differ their precision and
there was some individuals where telling
them did alter their
Precision but of course those Precision
estimates are features of a statistical
model which is why we had to construct
this those Precision estimates and the
statistics about how those Precision
estimates differ those are not features
of Simply the heart
rate
but this is a
big this is a big apparatus to bring
out so if you just are actually
interested in the descriptive
statistics if your question can be
addressed with description description
of behavior you literally don't need a
cognitive
model this is being brought out when you
are trying to make inference about
something that's not directly
objective yeah then they reference these
two papers that do have slightly
different ways of looking at this
IE Cade
situation um
again to this kind of basian
epistemology and also like sociology of
neurodiversity
really we hear so much rational
irrational irrational nonrational all
this um
and act active inference or just basing
epistemology has kind of like a simple
and a deflationary but also kind of a
maddening answer to that which is well
all the generative models are on their
path of least
action so those paths May
differ but the paths are all alike in
that they're all Paths of least action
so it's all based optimal one person
might be engaging in a repetitive
Behavior another person might be
ruminating another might be having
anxiety could be human could be nonh
human but those are all Paths of least
action um
so obviously there's a lot to say about
this but um that gives a little bit of a
space
between like disorder implies that
there's like an ordered and a
disordered but here it's saying
inference is working fine but on a flaw
generative model but again you could
even go further than that and say well
there's nothing flawed with
it
like so but that's the kind of way that
it takes that that
conversation table 91 reviews a bunch of
settings where these kinds of parameters
have been
done addiction impulsivity compulsivity
delusion hallucination interpersonal
personality
disorder oculomotor syndromes
pharmacotherapy prefrontal
syndromes that's seems pretty general
not sure that one is visual
neglect disorders of interceptive
inference and that's where the Ryan
Smith
work especially is
relevant and it's the
sumary so it's kind of an interesting
chapter with a few of these Mosaic
sections
beginning with a
large
scoping frame on cognitive behavioral
modeling then having these two kind
of
technical
subsections then going into a chapter
six like
interlude about how this work is
empirically deployed
providing two examples of generative
models in the ey tracking
setting going into this kind of like
social definitions of
pathology and empirical work on
pathology
space
summary
people who are interested in this like
design
Matrix or just like experimental
statistics
SPM textbook is really the place to
look
another kind of interesting note is
um the methods for active inference are
very welldeveloped
in the SPM toolkit in Matlab and so for
neuroimaging in those kinds of studies
there's a ton of empirical work however
most people who are in data science
today are not using Matlab using Python
and pmdp leading python active inference
package is only now beginning to
include these
empirical going from data to the
model type model inversion
tools those do exist in the Julia RX and
fur
World um which is one reason I believe
why such a common kind of paper today is
like we built a generative model
we synthesized some data we simulated
data because going from the data back to
the model is actually not so easy
today for a full active inference
model but as that becomes more
plausible there's going to be a whole
new Forest of lwh hanging fruit for
those who choose to forage
because this data could be any
data so this could be click data it
could be Ant foraging
data I mean these are just regular data
sets that people have already analyzed
and then it will be a purely empirical
question what cognitive modeling can
add in comparison with purely
descriptive statistical methods
so as that capacity becomes like
unlocked in the active inference
ecosystem It won't always be like
situation generative model
simulation we'll be able to like start
with empirical data about real systems
economic data psychological data and so
on and then already have that while
we're having the generative model
discussion that's going to reduce a lot
of degrees of freedom on the generative
model because we're knowing that it's
going to interface with the data a
certain
way so honestly it's like a whole mode
of discourse and work in the oim space
that we just don't
see but this chapter lays it
out because where we do see that mode of
work is literally fris in at all's work
in mat lab with the SPN
package
is the SPM like textbook is that like on
the website for The Institute or is that
a something I should just be find online
I'll I'll um I'll put it in the chat I
believe that this is the most recent
yeah spm2
manual is probably the most
recent
[Music]
um this is probably one to look
at the last print version is this one
from
2007 so it has some
typos it
um is less about like action in the loop
and the control
theory
however the relationship between Sensor
Fusion and hidden State inference
neuronal Dynamics inference
this is absolutely a slam
dunk so it's very very and even just
like
[Music]
um e even just seeing the kinds of
statistical methods that are that are in
play
between neuroimaging observations and
then just the cognitive
modeling and
then having action
kind of come out of the neuronal
Dynamics one I think that that is not
the only learning path but I think that
that can give a more solid basis for the
kind of downstairs part of the
model um and then also when we're
talking about like attention as mental
action or covert action common theme
that's basically like saying well we
have this
descending um internal action
that's
intervening in Hidden State
dynamics that um so then it's kind of
like but but SPM is like the
train and then now it's like okay AC
action intervening in attention is like
you know I don't know throwing like
little throwing something in between the
spokes of the train wheel or having a
hand on the train
wheel but this
train
downstairs is basically St statistically
summarized in
SPM so it doesn't go as heavy into the
action embodiment all of these topics
that we like know and love as part of
the discourse
today
but I think it's a really useful
prerequisite or background work so
that's different from the manual that's
um
yeah
I I'm not exactly sure what the overlap
is between the manual and the 2007 book
um we should definitely use a language
model to find out I may or may not have
a PDF of this
book
um yeah and it just helps giv us a sense
of what friston at all were working
on only 15 years ago
primarily
and that helps contextualize like oh
this whole like
physics of cognitive systems versus just
the statistics of
neuroimaging but how how nicely they
come
together and as someone who's never done
neuroimaging it was just kind of cool to
like see the kinds of challenges that
they have and there's a lot of
transferable uh information like the
fmri Bold signal has like a latency of
several seconds so you know it takes two
seconds to come on and it takes 10
seconds to fade off or something so then
if you're timing experimental
stimuli the stimuli can't come in every
half a second but also if you wait five
minutes you're going to reduce your
statistical power because you only have
a fixed amount of time in a
scanner so like these are like very
empirical
very pragmatic
aspects so it just makes me think about
how in kind of future textbook groups or
future internships or whatever it is
like there's the Journey of chapter six
there's you know Journey on the low road
and high road then there's the journey
on chapter six to build a generative
model for a situation of
interest and then there's the the
Journey of doing an
experiment
and of how you reckon with these
resource constraints and with um data
that don't uniquely identify models all
these different
things so there's a lot of a lot of cool
things
that chapter nine helps open
up any just
thoughts or or ideas that people are
having at this point in the
group um yeah I I find this chapter to
be just incredibly important as far as
application of active inference goes and
uh I I think it was great that you kind
of directed us to Ryan Smith's work and
others I think that um there are enough
general principles here for this chapter
to be used useful and that said uh
actually being able to see like direct
examples of the application in already
published Works um seems very you know
useful and that we we actually have
something kind of more concrete to to
get our hands
into
yeah so here's like interceptive
Precision so this is a this is a they
did parameter recovery on the a matrix
then you can say well what's the
correlation coefficient between this
coefficient we identified IP and these
empirical
phenomena Reaction Time Reaction Time
variability these are just descriptive
statistics but on the x axis the rows
are
precisions a difference in the Precision
prior learning rate and learning rate so
the rows are actually cognitive
parameters and then the columns are
empirical descriptive
statistics blue is a positive
correlation and red is a negative
correlation so this is like immensely
transferable if you think
about well the observations and the
summary statistics are on the blanket
so if you're just trying to draw
conclusions about just the
blanket
um you know there's a factory it's
making
blankets if you just wanted the average
color or the average size of the blanket
you could just measure but then if you
wanted to do some sort of inference
about what was happening in the factory
and then you could do this kind of
correlation between here's the outcomes
and here's the cognitive parameters that
might lead to those
outcomes this starts to really find some
[Music]
interesting possible because you and you
could also look at the correlations of
different cognitive
parameters and then here it is with the
statistical statistical
differences say well you know we we
don't find a statistically significant
relationship between interceptive
precision and
BMI negative slope but it's
just insignificantly different from
zero but we do find this statistical
relationship here
so
yeah and that's what differentiates
cognitive modeling from purely
behavioral work
okay well let's
see next week we
return second discussion on
nine there are some questions already on
nine and there's probably
also um a bunch more we can
add but we'll come back to nine next
week any last thoughts on
this yeah um you know maybe uh as an
extra thought maybe next week uh uh
unless there are any new incomers uh who
do want a refresher on as a summary or
something maybe going over another
example or two uh that you that you
could think of I mean even this just at
the very end was super helpful like the
the correlation graph between the
cognitive variables and um you know
collected data so if you had any
thoughts on maybe something like a
simple walkthrough or two or maybe
opening that up um could be really great
um yeah just the direct application in
the concrete example super super helpful
cool sounds good yeah maybe if you find
a paper that you
like then send to me and we can see if
it's um relevant or maybe we can look at
one of the papers in t
91 or one of one or two of these iade
papers okay or we can look at another
one but yeah cool all right thank you
everybody farewell thank you so much bye
thank you